# Ferdinand Haaben

#### **Software Developer**

(778) 917 8365 | ferdinand@haaben.net | BC, Canada | LinkedIn | ferdinand.haaben.net

## SUMMARY

Highly skilled Full Stack Software Developer with 2 years of experience in building sophisticated web applications from scratch. Proficient in modern web frameworks such as Django, Laravel, and Next.js. Eager to learn more and use my skills to provide value.

## SKILLS

Programming Languages: Javascript, Typescript, Python, Java, PHP

Frameworks: NodeJs, React, NextJs, Django, Laravel

DevOps: Linux, Github, Digital Ocean, Docker

Testing: Jest, Jenkins, Selenium

Soft Skills: Leadership, Proactive Communication, Problem-Solving, Presenting, Adaptability, Innovation

## EXPERIENCE

## Chief Technology Officer (CTO)

Virtulynx

Oct 2024 - Present Kelowna, BC

- · Built full stack web application from scratch using NextJs
- Integrated multiple APIs including OpenAi, and stripe
- · Designed front end user interface
- Designed database schema and server logic
- · Set up deployment through github actions and digital ocean

**Laravel Developer** Jun 2024 - Oct 2024 Nerd North Vernon, BC

- Designed and implemented backend architecture and database schema.
- · Created a responsive front-end interface using Tailwind, Alpine.js, and Livewire.
- · Conducted thorough testing and deployed the application to the production environment.
- Integrated multiple third-party APIs, including Printful and Stripe for seamless operations.
- · Managed the entire project lifecycle from requirements generation to final testing and deployment.

#### **Network Traffic Analyst**

Plume Design Inc

May 2023 - Sep 2023 Remote

- Configured OpenWRT router with Open VPN and tcpdump.
- Used custom command-line tools and Wireshark to analyze packets.
- Wrote "signatures" in a custom programming language to uniquely identify traffic.
- · Automated company processes with Python scripts.
- Analyzed large datasets with Pandas and Spark.

## **Junior Software Developer**

Ocean Networks Canada

- Victoria, BC
- · Created and maintained UI tests with Java + Selenium. • Designed and implemented front-end features with React.
- Implemented back-end services in Java.
- · Participated in scrum meetings, code reviews, and agile SDLC.

May 2022 - Dec 2022

# **PROJECTS**

#### Honors Thesis: Teaching with Al

Sep 2023 - Apr 2024

University Of British Columbia

- Developed an asynchronous question center utilizing a Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) approach to provide answers to student inquiries.
- Implemented a feedback mechanism enabling students to rate Al-generated responses as helpful or unhelpful, fostering continuous improvement.
- Integrated a review and update system for teaching staff to refine unhelpful answers, ensuring high-quality and accurate responses.
- Successfully integrated the system into an existing office hours queue infrastructure, enhancing its practicality and user-friendliness.

## **EDUCATION**

#### University of British Columbia - Okanagan (UBCO)

Bachelor of Science (B.A.Sc) in Computer Science (Honors). GPA: 3.9/4.33

Kelowna, BC Sep 2019 – June 2024

## **Northern Lights College**

Diploma in Aircraft Maintenance Engineering

Dawson Creek, BC Jan 2015 – June 2016

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- · Class 5 Driver's License
- · Possession & Acquisition License (PAL)
- Co-operative Education Program (UBCO)

## **AWARDS**

- Deputy Vice-Chancellor Scholarship, UBCO (2022-2023)
- · Dean's List, UBCO (2024)